Project TYPHOON ** **
Fallout Italian translation ** **

Edited by: Ragfox

---------------------

"Plus" version

---------------------

The "Plus" version and 'based on the patch "NPC 1.2.5" made by Pal that adds characters (and this) cut in the final version of the game. Here is revived in a revised version by me (Ragfox), which has taken steps to eliminate some bad characters implemented and put in place some of the problems of the original scripts.

---------------------

Table of Contents
  A. Installation
  B. Uninstall
  C. Warnings
  D. Additions (attention spoilers!)
  E. For more information

------
---------------


A. INSTALLATION

1. The "plus" version should be installed ONLY in conjunction with the Italian translation.

2. Make sure you have correctly installed Fallout, the patch 1.1 and the Italian translation (any version).

3. Run the file FOitaplus.exe.

4. Install the "Plus" in the same directory where you installed the translation
(Default: C: \ Program Files \ Interplay \ Fallout)

WARNING: saves made with only the translation may not be installed more 'usable once installed the "plus" version. If you want to try this add-on, you should install it before you start a new game.


B. UNINSTALL

1. The uninstallation of the "plus" version also brings out the patch 1.1 and the Italian translation. Sara 'then need to install them again at a later time.

2. Delete the folder / data contained in the root directory of Fallout

3. If you want to keep the bailouts (which may not be compatible with the only translation), copy the folder / data / savegame in a directory of your choice and then paste it back into the folder / data to the root directory of Fallout. Even for the data / sound do the same, unless it is decided to proceed with a new installation of the game.


C. WARNINGS

Test matches have been performed to check the stability 'General Fallout "plus" and the results were more' than satisfactory. However, due to the amateur nature of the patch on which the "plus" version, not 'can guarantee the perfect functioning of the game.

The author of this patch is not 'in any way responsible for any hardware and software problems that have occurred in the time period following the installation of this patch. The patch and 'just a collection of files that it does not change anything about it' to the operating system level it 'at the hardware level.


D. ADDITIONS

The reading of the following lines could be partially ruin the gaming experience, because they contain references to characters and environments that can be encountered in the early stages more 'advanced.


  Characters added

  Shady Sands
   Elder (dialogue and script rewritten by Ragfox)
   Agatha (original script and dialogue - opportunity 'to expand)
   Merchant
   Merchant's Bodyguard
    
  Junktown
   Bob
   Hernandez player (dialogue and script corrected and supplemented by Ragfox)

  Adytum
   Julianna, the lover of Romero

  Blade
   Fire (modified from Ragfox dialogue, script clearly flawed, but working)
   Beca / Jade (original dialogue, script clearly flawed, but working)
   Dolgan (modified from Ragfox dialogue, script clearly flawed, but working)
   Michelle (original dialogue, script clearly flawed, but working)
   Romero, the lover of Julianna
   Dragon

  Disciples
   Amber
   Nail (original dialogue, script slightly modified from Ragfox)
   Marney
   Jake
   Peter (original dialogue, script slightly modified from Ragfox)
   Heather
   Uthern (ok dialogue, scripts uncertain)
   Super Mutant (ok dialogue, scripts uncertain)
    
  Brotherhood
   Get them
   Brenden


E. For information and suggestions

Ragfox: drakenar@virgilio.it
Project TYPHOON: http://www.multiplayer.it/git/tifone